GAUTAM SAPRE

gautamsapre@gmail.com | (617)396-1452 | 1704 Yellowthroat Dr. Little Elm, TX, 75068 | linkedin.com/in/gautam-sapre | github.com/gautamsapre

SUMMARY

Results-driven and passionate software developer experienced with Programming languages such as JAVA, Python (Django), C++, TypeScript, ReactJS, etc, and technologies such as AWS, Azure DevOps, Git, Unix, etc. Enthusiastic full-stack developer with experience in database management. Has previous technical internship experience in software from Communications and Power Industries (CPI), and Amazon (AWS).

EXPERIENCE

Software Developement Engineer Intern, Amazon - AWS

May 2022 - Aug 2022

- Designed and implemented a new software feature for an extensive, distributed software application in a collaborative cross-team agile environment.
- Established a correct solution for a broadly defined problem, while ensuring performance, scalability, and usability.
- Exceeded predefined goals by 25% by achieving out-of-scope use cases through research and utilization of external resources.

Software Engineering Intern, Communication and Power Industries (CPI)

Nov 2020 - Mar 2022

- Assisted in a data migration project which included working with Azure DevOps and IBM RTC.
- Created Pipelines and Deployments in Azure for CPI's product line, e.g. Netmac which is an Antenna Control System.
- Explored Automated Testing solution for CPI's software products, worked with Test Complete, and reduce efforts of Test-Engineers by 20%.

Industry Lead, ACM - HackUTD

Dec 2019 - Feb 2021

- Managed a team of HackUTD Industry Coordinators to host the biggest hackathon in North Texas.
- Set up meetings and kept up to date with the teams work to make sure conflicts are getting cleared.
- Duties included maintaining relations with companies and accommodate their needs. And also figure out perks for each tier of the sponsorship packet. Contacted companies like Microsoft, Google, Walmart Tech, IBM, etc.

PROJECTS

Intelligent Air Quality - Murata Manufacturing Co.

- Enhanced an occupancy estimator using data regarding air quality of a closed room. Led the front-end team to create a dynamic website to depict data produced by the machine learning models.
- Utilized the Django web framework in Python to display data and model estimations in an organized and eye-appealing fashion. Technologies Used: Django, Python, and ReactJS.

Carpool

- Created an android application that lets users match with people to carpool with who have similar commutes.
- Implemented a chat application that lets the users talk to people matched with. Utilized the Firebase database to store users' data. Technologies used: Java (Android Studio), Google Autocomplete API and Firebase

SKILLS

Languages: JAVA, C++, Python, Javascript, TypeScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, Django, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, Markdown Technologies: Git, Linux, Unix, Firebase

Tools: AWS, Azure Devops, Github, Postman, Trello, Jira, Command Line, Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Cloud, Slack, Microsoft Teams

Soft: Entrepreneurship, Project Management, Adaptability, Conflict resolution, Communication Skills, Mentorship

Accomplishments

Organizations: Association of Computing Machinery (HackUTD): Industry Lead, Artificial Intelligence Society: Operations Coordinator

Awards: Academic Excellence Scholarship at the Honors Level Recipient

Courses: C/C++ in a Unix Environment, Computer Networks, Computer Architecture, Data Structures and Algorithms, Linear Algebra, Probability and Statistics in CS, Programming Languages, Advanced Algorithms, Virtual Reality

EDUCATION

Master's of Science, Computer Science - Data Science The University of Texas at Dallas Bachelor's of Science, Computer Science The University of Texas at Dallas

Aug 2022 - May 2024

Aug 2018 - May 2022